<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Advenatures in computing]]></title>
  <link href="http://jowrjowr.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jowrjowr.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-23T12:50:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jowrjowr.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Eric Gisse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time for a New Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://jowrjowr.github.io/blog/2014/10/23/time-for-a-new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-23T10:43:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jowrjowr.github.io/blog/2014/10/23/time-for-a-new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Time for a new blog</h1>

<h3>Who am I?</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m Eric, and I decided to start writing about various little projects and efforts I am working on. This has the dual benefits of putting myself out there in a positive light, and to document weirdnesses in various projects that I run that I would like to make public.</p>

<p>I work as an erstwhile Linux syadmin / consultant / developer. My principle focus at this point in time is <a href="http://www.puppetlabs.com">Puppet</a> configuration management, and the special hell that can occasioanlly turn into. Most of my work goes through oDesk, and you can see my oDesk profile <a href="https://www.odesk.com/o/profiles/users/_~01f2546e9a35daff31/">here</a>.</p>

<h3>What am I doing?</h3>

<p>Currently I&rsquo;m working on a fair number of client projects but the current interest that&rsquo;ll get the majority of my discussion time is properly teaching myself SELinux via building a fully secure Tor exit node on top of Gentoo, my preferred distribution for anything that deviates from the nice little box that the RHEL family builds for you.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also figuring out how to run Octopress as a blogging platform. Its&#8217; being a pain in the ass but I&rsquo;m getting the hang of it and I love it far more than the infinitely insecure Wordpress platform, which is such a piece of shit when it comes to security that it boggles the mind.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
